[
{
      "question":"Who among the following was the first famous and powerful king of Sen dynasty?",
      "optionA":"Ballal Sen",
      "optionB":"Vijay Sen",
      "optionC":"Samanta Sen",
      "optionD":"Vikram Sen",
      "correctAns":"Samanta Sen"
   },
   {
      "question":"What was the function of Samharta in Mauryan Administration?",
      "optionA":"To Collect Revenue",
      "optionB":"To Work as a Judge",
      "optionC":"Leadership of Army",
      "optionD":"Delivering Justice",
      "correctAns":"To Collect Revenue"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which among the following was main item of revenue during Maurya Period?",
      "optionA":"Bhaga",
      "optionB":"Pindikara",
      "optionC":"Hiranya",
      "optionD":"None of the above",
      "correctAns":"Bhaga"
   },
   {
      "question":"Evidence of a game which was very similar to chess was found at which of the following sites at Indus valley civilization?",
      "optionA":"Harappa",
      "optionB":"Lothal",
      "optionC":"Mohen Jo dero",
      "optionD":"Kalibangan",
      "correctAns":"Lothal"
   },
   {
      "question":"Nude male torso has been found at which of the following place?",
      "optionA":"Mehergarh",
      "optionB":"MohanJodro",
      "optionC":"Harappa",
      "optionD":"Lothal",
      "correctAns":"Harappa"
   },
   {
      "question":"Gandhar Kingdom of Later vedic phase was mostly located at which of the following places?",
      "optionA":"Afghanistan",
      "optionB":"Rawalpindi and Peshawar districts of Pakistan",
      "optionC":"Kashmir",
      "optionD":"Harappa",
      "correctAns":"Rawalpindi and Peshawar districts of Pakistan"
   },
   {
      "question":"Who among the following is seemed to have known the importance of zero?",
      "optionA":"Bhaskaracharya",
      "optionB":"Aryabhatta",
      "optionC":"Budhayana",
      "optionD":"chanukya",
      "correctAns":"Bhaskaracharya"
   },
   {
      "question":"Who was the founder of the Pala Dynasty of Bengal?",
      "optionA":"Dharmapala",
      "optionB":"Gopala",
      "optionC":"Mahendrapala",
      "optionD":"Mahipala",
      "correctAns":"Gopala"
   },
   {
      "question":"Painted Grey ware‚Äù was used in which of the following era?",
      "optionA":"Early Vedic Era",
      "optionB":"Later Vedic Era",
      "optionC":"Harappan Era",
      "optionD":"None of the above",
      "correctAns":"Later Vedic Era"
   },
   {
      "question":"Four Noble Truths are one of the most fundamental truths of which of the following religion?",
      "optionA":"Jainism",
      "optionB":"Buddhism",
      "optionC":"Islam",
      "optionD":"Hinduism",
      "correctAns":"Buddhism"
   }
]